An Inventory of the White House Conference on Child Health and Protection Records
Hoover Institution Archives
- 1 photographic print depicting construction of a church, undated (Folder 119: 11)
- Financial records (Box 120)
  - Correspondence and telegram, 1929. (Folder 120: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1930 January - June. (Folder 120: 2)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and telegram, 1930 July - December. (Folder 120: 3)
- Directory of committee personnel, 1930 (Folder 120: 4)
- Section IIIG, Youth Outside Home and School, 1930 and undated. (Folder 120: 5)
  Correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, reports, and statement
- 8 printing plates, undated (Folder 120: 6)
- Financial records (Box 121)
  - Statement of expenditures, 1929 June - November (Folder 121: 1)
  - Details for current vouchers, 1932-1934 and undated (Folder 121: 2)
  - Summaries and budget balance, 1932 and undated (Folder 121: 3)
  - Sales--Books and literature
    - 1931 February - 1932 April
    - 1932 November - 1933 January (Box 122)
  - Check records
    - 1931 May 1 - December 31
    - 1932 July 1 - 1933 January
  - Various committees and sections, 1930-1931 (Box 123)
  - Section ledger--Transfer, 1929-1930
  - Cancelled checks, 1932-1933, and unused checks
  - New checkbooks, undated
- 4 printing plates, undated
- Report of the Subcommittee on the Schools of the Philippine Islands, undated (Box-folder 124: 1)
- Committee on Recreation and Physical Education, Section IIIE, undated. (Folder 124: 2-3)
  Notes, report, statistical data, study, training program, and related materials
- The Story of The American Child Health Association by Philip Van Ingen, 1935 (Folder 124: 4)
- Child Welfare Magazine, 1927 April (Folder 124: 5)
- "The San Francisco Juvenile Court: A Study of Its Organization and Functions,", 1935 (Folder 124: 6)
- Miscellany, 1923-1935. (Folder 124: 7)
  Correspondence and minutes of the meeting of Subcommittee on Juvenile Court, Committee on Community Plan for Child Welfare, and printed matter, 1923-1935
- Data on extent and kind of health education available in normal schools in 1922. (Box-folder 125: 1)
  Includes tabulation of questionnaires sent out by the Child Health Organization of America, undated
- Report of Skidmore College, Saratoga Springs, New York, 1926 and undated. (Folder 125: 2)
  Chart, correspondence, poster, and survey. Includes 2 photographic prints depicting unidentified buildings
- International health education conferences
  - First health education conference, Lake Mohonk, New York, 1922. (Folder 125: 3)
    Correspondence, printed matter, report, statement of expenditure, and miscellany
  - Second health education conference, San Francisco, California, 1923. (Folder 125: 4)
    Brochure, memoranda, poster, report, and related materials
- American Child Health Association--Scholarships and fellowships, 1923-1924. (Folder 125: 5)
  Announcements, application, correspondence, lists of guests invited to the luncheon and names and addresses of Health Education Division scholarship students, minutes of meeting, and related materials
- Thousand Dollar Fellowship offered by the Child Health Organization of America, 1920. (Folder 125: 6)
  Announcement, application, outline, and related materials
- Report on scholarship project sponsored by East Harlem Health Center and the American Child Health Association, 1923. (Folder 125: 7)
  Extracts from papers submitted for contest, memoranda, and related materials
- Report--Teacher education study of the teaching of hygiene in fifty institutions, 1925 (Folder 125: 8)
- Historical materials, 1923-1926. (Folder 125: 9-11)
  Alphabetical list of cities participating in a contest, brochure, conference proceedings, correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, report, and related materials
- School health programs (Box 126)
  - Self-analysis of secondary school health programs, 1924-1927. (Folder 126: 1)
    Case study and related materials, correspondence, and financial records. Also includes Health Trends in Secondary Education
  - School health program contest, 1924-1925. (Folder 126: 2)
    Guidelines for evaluation of the program, outline form for reporting the study for schools, press release, and statement
  - Sally Lucas Jean and Julia Wade Abbott's visit to the Panama Canal zone and Republic of Panama, 1924 January - February. (Folder 126: 3)
    Correspondence between Sally Lucas Jean and Wesley Cintra Cox, expense accounts, memorandum, and report
  - "Suggestive Outline for Health Teaching in the Schools of the Panama Canal Zone," prepared by the representatives of the American Child Health Association, 1924 January (Folder 126: 4)
  - Manuscripts submitted in scholarship contest and selected as reflecting the prevalent situation, 1925 (Folder 126: 5-17)
  - "Hygiene Outline: Grades I-VIII," Margaret F. Shaw, Territorial Normal School, Honolulu, 1920 (Folder 126: 18)
- Health education conferences (Box 127)
  - Cambridge health education conference convened by the American Child Health Association, Cambridge, sponsored by the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1924 June 23-28. (Folder 127: 1)
    Financial record, list of invitees, memorandum, report, and schedule
  - Fourth health education conference, University of Chicago, Illinois, 1925. (Folder 127: 2)
    Financial records, lists of guests and magazines for conference papers, map, memoranda, press releases, plan, printed matter, program, proceedings of the conference, report, and statement
  - Fifth health education conference, Sayville, Long Island, convened by the American Child Health Association (1929 June 17-22) (Folder 127: 3)
    Abstracts of reports, map, proceedings of the conference, program, schedule, statement, and 3 photographic prints including 1 depicting members of conference, 1 depicting members of the general group, and I depicting members of the Fifth health education conference and of Middle and Far West Group
  - First health conference, Baguio, Mountain Province, Philippine Island, 1929 and undated. (Folder 127: 4)
    Certificate of welcome, list of members, schedule, and miscellany. Includes a painting depicting an outdoor scenery and 2 photographic prints depicting members, undated
  - Sixth health education conference, Sayville, Long Island, New York (1930 June 16-21), 1929-1930. (Box-folder 128: 1)
    Chart, financial record, press release, organization of the conference, printed matter, and program schedule. Includes 3 photographic prints depicting members of general group, California group, and Massachusetts. Includes Principles and Practices in Health Education, Sayville conference, Long Island, New York, 1930 June 16-21
  - Seventh health education conference, University of Michigan Ann Arbor, Michigan (1933 June 20-24), 1933-1934. (Folder 128: 2)
    Brochure, bulletin, letter, program, report, statement, and other related materials
  - Eighth health education conference, University of Iowa, Iowa City, Iowa (1935 June 19-22) (Folder 128: 3)
    Brochure, financial record, list of attendees, memoranda, press release, program, publicity report, statement, and other related materials. Includes Principles and Practices in School Health Education, 1935
- Tentative course of study in health education for public schools of Tulsa, Oklahoma, Grades I-VIII--Metropolitan scholarship, submitted by Myrtle Elizabeth Barker, University of Chicago, 1924 (Box-folder 129: 1)
- "A Study of the Group Lunch as a Means of Solving Some Problems in Feeding the Pre-School Child," dissertation submitted by Myrtle Elizabeth Barker to the faculty of the Ogden Graduate School of Science for the degree of Master of Science, Department of Home Economics, University of Chicago, Illinois, 1924 August (Folder 129: 2)
- Metropolitan scholarship
  - Case history and report, 1924. (Folder 129: 3)
    Brochure, correspondence, list of recipients of the scholarship and committee members, map, memoranda, and report, and other related materials. Includes Teachers' Health Diary Notebook, 1923 November 12 - 1924 May 15
- American Child Health Association (A.C.H.A.)
  - Traveling Fellowship reports
    - Clara M. Greenough, 1923-1924 (Folder 129: 4)
    - Bessie Noyes, 1923-1924 (Folder 129: 5)
  - Scholarship
    - "Hygienic Living and Health Teaching in Elementary School," dissertation by Herman Pinkerton, Wilson County, Tennessee, 1923-1924 (Folder 129: 6)
    - "An Investigation of Some of the Hygienic Needs of New York City High School Boys as Found at the DeWitt Clinton High School," by Paul Thompson, New York, 1923-1924 (Folder 129: 7)
  - Health education conferences and programs (Box-folder 130: 1-3)
    - Report of an informal conference on health education in teacher training institutions, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1925 February 19-21.
      Includes letters, list of attendees of the conference, memoranda, minutes of meeting, outline of a program and report, and questionnaire
    - Records of world service: American Child Health Association Educational Series in cooperation with health sections of the World Federation of Education Associations Conferences
      - San Francisco, 1923. (Folder 130: 4)
        Financial record
      - Edinburgh, Scotland, 1925. (Folder 130: 5)
        Correspondence, memoranda, report, and related materials1
      - League of Nations, 1925-1926. (Folder 130: 6)
        Correspondence regarding historical value
      - Second biennial conference, University of Toronto, Canada, 1927-1928. (Folder 130: 7)
        Printed matter, program, and related materials
      - Third biennial conference, Geneva, Switzerland, 1929-1930. (Folder 130: 8)
        Correspondence, financial record, questionnaire, and statement
      - L. Emmett Holt, 1930. (Folder 130: 9)
        Correspondence and related materials
      - Fourth biennial conference, Denver, Colorado, 1931-1932. (Folder 130: 10)
        Correspondence, minutes of meeting, and record of registration
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company--Fellowship traveling, administered by Miss Dolfinger and Anita S. Dowell, 1925. (Folder 130: 11)
      Correspondence, list of teacher training institution candidates registering for the conference, and report
    - Materials provided by Miss Dowell, winner of fellowship, 1925 (Folder 130: 12)
    - Cooperative study of school health program in schools of the Mesabi Iron Range, Minnesota, by Lucy Oppen, 1926-1927. (Folder 130: 13-14)
      Correspondence, memoranda, and report
    - Minutes of meetings, 1922-1935. (Box-folder 131: 1-2)
      Includes article, correspondence, and record of disbursement
    - Annual report to the Executive Committee, 1935 February 19 (Folder 131: 3)
    - "Suggestions for Three Community Studies,", 1931 (Box-folder 132: 1)
    - Statistical reports of infant mortality for cities in the United States
      - 519 cities for 1920; 665 cities for 1923; 667 cities for 1924; 697 cities for 1925 675 cities for 1926; and 716 cities for 1927 (Folder 132: 2)
      - 729 cities for 1928 and 1929; 874 cities for 1930; 892 cities for 1931; 955 cities for 1932; and 985 cities for 1933 and 1934 (Folder 132: 3)
    - May Day materials, 1924-1930. (Folder 132: 4-5)
      Printed matter and program
    - Statements relating to the health campaign and summary report of the health conferences, 1930 and undated (Folder 132: 6)
- Children's Charter, 1931. (Box 133)
  Plates and receipts of cuts, 1931
- Reports (Box 134)
  - Committee of Recreation and Physical Education, Henry Breckinridge, chairman, undated (Folder 134: 1-2)
  - Juvenile Delinquency--Summary memorandum of available material on extent, causes, treatment, and prevention, 1929 (Folder 134: 3)
  - Committee A, Section III
    - Subcommittee on the Function of Home Activities in the Education of the Child, E. W. Burgess, chairman, 1930 August (Folder 134: 4)
    - Subcommittee on Education for Home and Family Life at the Elementary and Secondary Levels, Louise Stanley, chairman of Committee A, and Anna A. Richardson, chairman, subcommittee, 1931 February (Folder 134: 5)
  - Committee A, Section I, Growth and Development (Box 135)
    - General considerations
      - Division I, Part I, undated (Folder 135: 1)
      - Division I, Part II, undated (Folder 135: 2)
    - Morphological and functional considerations
      - Division II, Part I, undated (Folder 135: 3)
      - Division II, Part II, undated (Folder 135: 4)
      - Division II, Part III, undated (Folder 135: 5)
    - Nutrition
      - Division III, Part I, undated (Folder 135: 6)
      - Division III, Part III, undated (Folder 135: 7)
    - Mental development--Division IV, undated (Folder 135: 8)
    - Nutrition--Division III, Part II, undated (Box-folder 136: 1)
  - Section IIB, Committee on Communicable Disease Control, George H. Bigelow, chairman, 1930 September and November (Folder 136: 2-3)
  - Section IIC, Committee on Milk and Milk Production and Control, H. A. Whittaker, chairman, 1930 (Folder 136: 4)
  - Committee A, Section III
    - Subcommittee on Education for Home and Family Life at the Elementary and Secondary Level, Anna E. Richardson, chairman, 1931 February (Folder 136: 5)
    - Subcommittee on the Function of Home Activities in the Education of the Child, E. W. Burgess, chairman, 1930 August (Folder 136: 6)
  - Committee on Vocational Guidance and Child Labor, Anne S. Davis, Chairman (Box 137)
    - Volume I and II, Section III, Education and Training, F.J. Kelly, chairman. Summary Report
    - Part I, General Summary of Information and Recommendations, report of the Subcommittee on the Child Laborer in Non-Agricultural Occupations, 1930 October
    - Subcommittee on the Employment of Children in Agriculture, 1930 November
    - Subcommittee on Hazardous Occupations, Industrial Accidents, and Compensation for Minors, 1930 November
    - Subcommittee on the Schools of Puerto Rico, José Padin, chairman, Committee on the School Child; Thomas D. Wood, chairman, Section III; and Education and Training, F. J. Kelly, chairman, undated
    - Subcommittee on Indian Schools, Section IIIC, Committee on the School Child, Thomas D. Wood, chairman, undated
  - Committee on the Family and Parent Education, Louis Stanley, chairman, report, 1930 October (Box 138)
    - Committee A, Section III
      - Subcommittee on the Relation of Density and Aggregation of Population to the Family, 1930 October.
        Preliminary report
      - Subcommittee on Education for Home and Family Life at the Elementary and Secondary Levels, Anna E. Richardson, 1931 February.
    - Section III, Committee IIIA, Subcommittee number 5, Part II, Types of Parent Education, Content, and Method, Sidonie M. Gruenberg, undated
    - Section III, Committee A, Subcommittee number 3, Negro Family Life, by Ernest R. Groves, 1930 October
    - Committee IIIC, The School Child, Thomas D. Wood, chairman, Subcommittee on Professional Training of Teachers and Leaders, William C. Bagley, chairman, undated
  - Committee A, Section I (Box 139)
    - Growth and Development
      - Preliminary report of Division V, Determination of Physical Status, undated (Folder 139: 1)
      - Preliminary report of Division VI, Disease, undated (Folder 139: 2)
  - Section IV, Committee A
    - Abstract of the report of the Committee on State and Local Organizations for the Handicapped, Kate Burr Johnson, chairman, undated (Folder 139: 3)
    - Subcommittee on Organization and Equipment of State Departments, Committee on State and Local Organizations for the Handicapped, 1931 January (Folder 139: 4)
  - Committee IVC-2, Delinquency, "Children Violating Postal Laws Arrested in 1928: A Study of Records of the Post Office Department," prepared by Elizabeth Cosgrove, 1930 November (Folder 139: 5)
  - Subcommittee on the Administration of Local Public Units of Child Care (including county, township and regional), 1931 April (Folder 139: 6)
  - "Report of the Subcommittee on the School Plant: Its Construction, Equipment, Maintenance and Sanitation," N. L. Engelhardt, chairman, Committee on the School Child; Thomas D. Wood, chairman, Section III; and Education and Training, F. J. Kelly, chairman, undated (Folder 139: 7)
  - Section IIIC, Committee on the School Child, Thomas D. Wood, chairman
    - Subcommittee on Parochial Schools, undated (Folder 139: 8)
    - Subcommittee on Physical Education, undated (Folder 139: 9)
    - Subcommittee on the Negro School Child, undated (Folder 139: 10)
    - Subcommittee on Summer Vacation Activities of the School Child, undated (Folder 139: 11)
  - Section III, Committee IIIA, Subcommittee number 5, Part I, Types of Parent Education, Content and Method, Sidonie M. Gruenberg, chairman, undated (Folder 139: 12)
  - Joint Committee on Statistics, Henry W. Thurston, chairman, Section IV, The Handicapped: Prevention, Maintenance, Protection, C. C. Carstens, chairman, undated (Folder 139: 13)
- Mother and Child: A Magazine Concerned with their Health, Volume IV, Number 1, 1923 January (Box 140)
- Fargo and the Health Habits, by Maud A. Brown, 1928 June
- Physical Measures of Growth and Nutrition, School Health Research Monographs, Number II, 1929
- Public Health Aspects of Dental Decay in Children, School Health Research Monographs, Number III, 1930
- White House conference: Addresses and abstracts of committee reports, 1930
- Program: Health education conference, Sayville, Long Island, New York, 1929 June 17-22
- Principles and Practices in Health Education, Sayville, Long Island, New York, 1930 June 16-21
- May Day
  - National Child Health Day, 1931
  - Child Health Day in 1932: Suggestions for 1933
- Health Education Conference, Ann Arbor, Michigan (1933 June), 1931-1933.
  Newsletters, list of publications of the White House conference, and a copy of the Children's Charter
- Advances in Health Education, 1934
- White House happenings, 1931 November - 1932 December. (Box-folder 141: 1)
  Newsletters. Includes list of publications of White House conference, undated, and copy of Children's Charter, 1931
- Child health bulletins and cumulative Index, 1925-1935
- Health education conference, 1930 June 16-21
- School Health Progress, health education conference, Sayville, Long Island, New York, 1929 June 17-22
- Child health demonstration, Mansfield and Richland County, Ohio, 1922-1925.
- A World Panorama of Health Education, 1930
- Health Section Report, 1932
- Principles and Practices in School Health Education, 1935
- Committee on the School Child, Thomas D. Wood, chairman (Box 142)
  - Report of the Subcommittee on Migrant School Child, Charles F. Willis, chairman, and Section III, Education and Training, F. J. Kelly, chairman, undated
  - Reports of the Subcommittees on the Indian Schools and the Schools of Alaska, Edna Groves and Jonathan H. Wagner, chairmen, undated
  - Report of the Subcommittee on School Health Legislation, James F. Rogers, chairman, undated
  - Report of the Subcommittee on School Health Surveys, E. S. Evenden, chairman, undated
  - Report of the Subcommittees on the Schools of the Philippine Islands and the Schools of Hawaii, Clotilde Patton Sanguinet and W. C. Crawford, chairmen, undated (Box 143)
  - Report of the Subcommittee on the Schools of the Panama Canal Zone, N. L. Engelhardt and José Padin, chairmen, undated
  - Report of the Subcommittee on Physical Education in Schools, Section IIIC, J. R. Sharman, chairman, undated
- "The School Health Program of the Island of Puerto Rico: A Discussion of some Present Problems and Future Developments," by Anna Leslie Whitney, 1931
- Directory of committee personnel, 1930 July 1
- Miscellany, undated
- American Child Health Association (A.C.H.A.) (Box 144)
  - Aida de Acosta Breckinridge, 1930 and undated. (Folder 144: 1)
    Correspondence, map, monthly report, newsletter, and note
  - Hetty Lovejoy Sorden, 1931. (Folder 144: 2)
  - Ione P. Hartford, 1931-1932. (Folder 144: 3)
    Correspondence, press release, and telegram
  - Miscellany, 1925-1930 and undated. (Folder 144: 4)
    Correspondence, printed matter including Declaration of the Rights of the Child, press release, and telegram
- Oversize material (Box 145)
  - 11 sketches, including 4 framed sketches, depicting the White House Conference on Child Health and Protection, undated, and 7 unframed sketches depicting Abraham Lincoln, Herbert Hoover, and children, copies of The Children's Charter, 1931 and undated
  - The Children's Charter, undated (Box 146)
  - Local conferences on child health and protection--Scrapbook, 1931-1932 and undated. (Box 147)
    Annual report, brochure, correspondence, map, organizational chart, press release, printed matter, and program describing the activities relating to the children's conference by the name of the states
  - Financial records, 1931-1933 and undated (Box 148-153)